Michael Allen

Senior Front End Developer

Contact

07925292700

michael@uplord.co.uk linkedin.com/in/themichael themichael.co.uk An experienced Front End Developer with a strong track record in collaboration, organization, and teamwork, coupled with a meticulous eye for detail. I am deeply passionate about crafting web experiences using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, and I maintain an open-minded approach to embracing emerging technologies. Over the past nine years, I have worked with a diverse range of clients, honing my analytical, debugging, and problem-solving abilities, all of which contribute to my ability to produce outstanding websites.

Education

Dundee, Scotland

Bachelor of Science (Hons)

Abertay University

Web Design and Development

Higher National Diploma

Dundee College

Computing Software Development

Skills

Javascript

(ES6, Vue3, Nuxt3, React, Typescript)

CSS

(Sass)

HTML

Responsive Web Design Wordpress

(Woocommerce)

APIs

(OpenAl, Wordpress, Youtube, Facebook, Instagram, Twitter)

Tools

(VS Code, Git, Github, Bitbucket, Webpack, Gulp, AWS, Firebase, Lighthouse, Netlify)

Design

(Figma, Sketch, Photoshop)

iOS development

(Objective C, Swift)

Work Experience

Senior Front End Developer

Snappy Shopper | Sept 2021 - Present

I rejoined Hungrrr right before the merger with Snappy Shopper and resumed my leadership role in Hungrrr's front-end development while supporting the Snappy Shopper team. My responsibilities included modernizing and enhancing the ordering platform and improve user experiences for clients and team members. I've also managed hundreds of client websites, implementing periodic updates to enhance their performance and boost sales. In addition, I worked on optimizing the B2B websites, streamlining the signup process, and efficiently tracking new leads, ultimately increasing client inquiries and platform engagement.

Front End Developer

mtc | Sept 2015 - Sept 2021

During my time at MTC, I've excelled in various company roles, from project leadership to client aftercare. I've adeptly handled complex projects from the outset, requiring minimal assistance, and I've also mentored new team members. I consistently meet tight deadlines without compromising quality and I demonstrated my adaptability by effortlessly working together with various teams. Additionally, I've contributed significantly to our internal codebase, benefiting new and ongoing projects company-wide. I've also taken the lead in front-end client support, alleviating team workload and fostering client relationships. My efficient workload management ensures timely completion of tasks for multiple clients.

Front End Developer

Hungrrr May 2020 - July 2020

At the onset of the pandemic, I assumed a leadership role in the company's frontend department. I spearheaded the integration of a table ordering system aimed at assisting businesses during their reopening phase, enhancing user experiences. Additionally, I played a pivotal role in the creation of an internal business setup tool, streamlining the process of adding new businesses to our system and facilitating client management for our team. My contributions were so impactful that I continued to work on projects for the company even after returning to MTC, highlighting the significant mark I left in a relatively short span of time.